Neelanshi Sharma

sharmaneelanshi00@gmail.com +91 - 7983881736 https://github.com/ns-github14 https://www.linkedin.com/in/neelanshisharma

Programming skills in Java, C and C++. Hands-on experience with Android Studio, Adobe XD, VS Code and Oracle. Leadership and management proficiency in event management and planning. Ardency for creative writing, culture talks and socializing.

EDUCATION

Banasthali Vidyapith, Jaipur, Rajasthan

Jul 2017 – May 2021

Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science Engineering) CGPA: 8.79

EXPERIENCES

Heartfulness Institute, Hyderabad

Jul 2020 - Present

Frontend Development Intern

- Democratize web functionality for effective addition, update and deletion of elements in a website.
- Designed responsive components in React using Storybook and Office Fabric React UI.

Banasthali Vidyapith, Jaipur, Rajasthan

Sept 2020 - Present

Project Trainee (Mobile Application Development)

- Full-stack development of a MedTrack using Android SDK and Google APIs.
- Designing frontend using XML and backend using Cloud Firestore in Firebase.

Mayukh'20, Banasthali Vidyapith, Jaipur

Jan 2020 – March 2020

Sub Core Team Member (Team Workshop)

- Organized, regulated and managed tech and non-tech workshops on trending industrial subjects.
- Conducted interview for in-house workshops.

COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

- Computer languages: C++, Java, HTML/CSS, SQL, Python, ReactJS
- Software: NetBeans, VS Code, Android Studio, NetBeans, Oracle, Storybook, Adobe XD, AWS
- Major Subjects: Android Application Development, AI and Machine Learning, Java, Data Communication and Networks, DSA, C++, OS Unix, Databases SQL & Oracle, Software Engineering SDLC

PROJECTS

MedTrack – A pill reminder-appointment booking application

- Developing this app using Java in Android Studio and implements Android SDK and Google APIs.
- Responsive frontend layout using XML and backend using Cloud Firestore in Firebase

GuacOn – A college meal planning application

- Integrating XML layouts and Cloud Firestore database in Android Studio using different dependencies.
- Creating API for faster and relevant retrieval of recipes and their details from the web.

WILSAC - An event registration website for technical clubs in university

- Server-side programming using JSP enabling dynamic, platform-independent method creation.
- Maintained Apache Derby database and used JDBC API for CRUD operations.

CERTIFICATIONS & VIRTUAL EXPERIENCE

- 1. Surface Computing, Data Analytics Workshop.
- 2. Overall **Technical Winner**, Mayukh'18 Technical Fest, Banasthali Vidyapith.
- **3. Android** Application Development Certification.
- **4. AWS** Building Serverless Application by Coursera.
- 5. JPMorgan Chase & Co. Software Engineering Virtual Experience
 - Interface with a stock price data feed
- 6. Accenture Discovery Program
 - Project Priorities and Planning
 - User Journey Redesign & Client Communication
- 7. BCG Open Access Design Virtual Experience Program
 - Strategic Design

- Display data visually for traders
- Outcomes Analysis
- Prioritization & Impact Assessment
- Experience Design